#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/quanyu2015 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

R programming
Data Analysis
Machine Learning

### Certifications

Practical Machine Learning
Data Visualization
Deep Learning Specialization
Natural Language Processing
Specialization
Machine Learning

# Yu QUAN

Data Scientist at Singapore Airlines Singapore

## Summary

My PhD study on human genetics using a large amount of sequencing and microarray data leads me to the world of data science. I've gained years of experience in R programming, data manipulation, data visualization, and statistical modelling from multiple research projects. As a self-motivated learner, I keep on learning new techniques from online courses. In 2019, I finished my part-time master courses at NUS. Currently, I'm working on industrial problems including predictive modelling, NLP, audio analysis and specialised in solving optimisation problems.

## Experience

Singapore Airlines
Data Scientist
March 2018 - Present (3 years 2 months)
Singapore

- Solve manpower scheduling problem and customer time slot allocation problem
- Optimize aircraft assignment using constrained optimization
- · Machine learning model to predict flight delay
- Text classification using NLP techniques
- · Audio classification using deep learning
- · Data visualizations and dashboards, data processing pipeline using Pyspark

National University of Singapore Research Fellow October 2015 - March 2018 (2 years 6 months)

- Developing novel analytical methods to detect genetic regulatory effect on gene expression using unsupervised learning and statistical tests.
- Process and explore large amount of next-generation sequencing data using R, ggplot2, Perl in a Linux environment. Present findings and insights to my professor.

## Education

National University of Singapore

Master of Technology in Knowledge Engineering (MTech KE), Data

Science · (2017 - 2019)

National University of Singapore
Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Bioinformatics (2015)

Xiamen University
Bachelor, Biotechnology